You're welcome.
Hello.
>> Wizard. Wizard.
>> Wizard.
>> You were so quick with that.
Hopefully
they'll have some [ __ ] in there to help
lead you back to wherever the [ __ ]
they're operating from.
Then you can um well kick the hornets
nest.
I don't know.
Yeah.
She likes the pretty comment.
Take her hand now.
>> Wait, everybody likes being called
pretty. Don't you like being called
pretty?
>> Uh, I suppose.
>> Don't you like,
>> my darling? You are very beautiful, my
dear.
>> I need to hug you for a second.
>> But look, other than that,
>> Oh, sure. That does sound pretty nice.
>> Is that what love looks like?
>> Yeah. Your guys
>> for me.
Huh? Uh uh. Okay. Wait. Wait. You don't
know what love looks like?
>> I I don't either.
>> It's different for you.
>> Both don't.
>> Well, I know it looks different for
everybody.
>> It's different for
>> Okay. I know. You're right.
>> How would I know love when I'm always
dying?
>> Whoa.
Okay.
>> Uh, right. So, um,
let's see. How do I explain it? When you
love someone,
>> it's like everything about them just
makes you laugh. Makes you sort of
>> blush and stuff. And
it's like a feeling that can't be
defined by just normal means.
It can be a lot of different things.
Some people might feel safe around their
significant other.
Hello.
Oh.
>> Hello.
Yeah.
>> It's okay. I understand. I understand.
>> I can't wait to see where the [ __ ]
disappointed mom stance. What is this?
>> I'm going to go to the church.
>> I don't know, man. What the [ __ ] do you
want me to do, bro? Actually,
you know what? I can't blame you. I
can't blame you. I'm sorry. I've been
standing for like the past couple hours.
>> Now they have an idea.
>> Part of me wants to go. Part of me says
I don't know if that's a good idea. On
one hand, great research opportunity. On
the other hand,
>> hello.
>> Did you find it? I am not.
>> No, but
>> if you say so.
>> I've studied the fay. I know they can be
really tricky stuff. Elves, I'm not sure
in my life.
>> Yeah, but that's the whole point.
supposed to be the whole, not like the
little bits of it chopped up into a
cigarette.
>> I don't want to hear from you, smoker.
>> Hey, at least I have experience,
jackass.
>> You know what?
>> Objection.
>> She didn't say she likes to take cold
showers.
>> Whoa. Uhoh. The lieutenant's back in
town.
>> You missed the field trip.
>> Yeah, it's unfortunate.
It
>> was exciting.
>> Got sucked up into a lay line.
>> Not done. So perhaps you can join us on
our next expedition.
>> Step could be worse.
>> Step
one of those.
I'm learning so much today
on the table.
>> I will of course uh let you know when I
am able to go to ingot. So you may join
and whoever wishes to uh also be of
interest.
You're about to get a lot of
>> It's not going well.
>> No, it's probably not going to. There
was some [ __ ] [ __ ] Okay,
>> I left for five minutes.
>> What do you mean?
>> You said there was some [ __ ] [ __ ] I
left the stove. What happened? The whole
thing is [ __ ] [ __ ] It's fine.
>> Uh before everyone uh flooding in,
perhaps we should get it over with while
we still have the chance to talk about
like 10 other people. Uh
>> we can go up to um Halifax's old room at
the top.
>> Oh, I wouldn't assume, but it
>> everyone's on their way. Obviously,
we'll cross that bridge when we get
there. will be time.
>> Hey, I don't
>> at this point,
>> you know, at this point, we'll probably
burn that bridge when we get there.
>> Yes.
>> The most uh advanced place and they
can't
disabled or the elderly.
>> Oh, here you go.
>> Hands you a bottle of fire brand
whiskey.
>> Ain't much, but you gave me something
really good.
>> I'll save it for later.
If I stand if I sit down, I won't be
able to stand up again.
>> Think of it this way.
>> In that case,
>> that's fair. That is absolutely fair.
>> Make a copy of the star chart I put
together while we were over there.
We made some truths.
>> Oh no.
>> What?
>> I just got a sending
>> uh one of my battle brothers may be
joining us and I'm slightly worried.
>> Friend
my time in the military uh dealing with
the fake court.
So, you were part of a FA military or
you were at war with a FA court?
>> I was part of the FA court. Uh,
specifically the autumn court. Uh, was
scripted for at least two campaigns.
>> Uh,
>> in place of my father since he was
unwell.
>> Specifically, they're ones that
mentioned it.
>> That doesn't matter.
>> Other f
Yeah. And he's a mercenary
>> and during that time
>> long story short of ancient
>> I want to say it might have been the
spring.
>> We had a we we had scuffles with the
spring but the main issue at least my
force was specifically dealing with was
the uh
>> winter court. How about
the ent
so we don't accidentally overhear
something that we don't need to
>> is there
>> I am not going to stand up because I
know what happens if I try to stand up
>> so I'm going to cheat
>> as I always do
>> afraid
>> I'd like to conserve my mana
>> oh I'm not using any mana the boots are
Enchanted
>> perhaps it could be something
each other.
The purpose purpose of the mag's guild
is first and foremost education.
>> And so if you wish to learn, we are
happy to
cont.
>> I'm still waiting for
now.
>> Easily distracted
>> with everything that's happened. You
would think
language that predates old magic. And
yet,
>> you'd also think that they would want a
few moments
in order to
>> Why, that'd actually be wonderful.
Allow me to learn more about well,
things I never actually had the chance
to.
And perhaps even if you would like
have my own
What name would you like me to?
I think civil will will be just fine.
Spell that for me. S I B L E.
>> I am having difficult Oh. Uh, we were
waiting for people. We were inside and
then we walked out. Well,
>> why would you normal continue to wait
inside where it's warmer?
>> In order to see what was taking people
so long.
That could be any number of things.
>> How am I going to close
>> back? When do you plan to have this
lesson for
>> I'm not an
I was under the impression that everyone
was coming here relatively soon.
>> Slowly coming back, but then a bunch of
people got distracted. Other people
started talking.
>> Told you.
Why is there
>> a
purpose to a gathering or am I just
hearing about a gathering?
>> I'm just here.
>> Yes.
any
is this going to be for discussions
regards to
>> particular topics or
>> do you want me to close
>> leave it open for everyone else to come?
>> I mean you I don't feel temperature so
it's literally up to you guys.
>> Preferably closed
>> but also what do you mean what just
happened?
A bunch of us just went to go see why
this is happening via the lay lines and
um
>> the short version is it's not good.
>> Oh, never mind. I'm having difficulty
grasping the
>> bad.
>> Is it frozen over?
>> It might have been frozen.
>> The knob might have frozen over.
>> Ah, yeah. I can't touch it. Now I just
need to find
>> this is why we can't have nice things.
>> Okay. But yes,
>> that's delegating.
>> I mean it was open when I got here which
I also thought was a little odd.
>> So something horrible has happened with
the lay lines is what I'm is what I'm
hearing. relief has been
>> your shoulder.
>> Yeah, the short version is bad, but it's
not like
>> it's not a life
bad, but it's
>> most people just walked around source
trying to see.
>> I shall bother you no more. However, I
will contact you in the days to come
with further information and updates if
I were to receive them. And I will let
you know when we are ready to go to
whenever
Take care, small tail.
>> And if you require me in the future, you
know where to find me.
>> Um, I actually
give your sending stone.
>> That's going to be an undertaking.
>> Wonderful.
>> We got the stone right there for
>> We're not apocalyptic. Would
>> you like to
open the door open? some new faces and
so I should do my job as a
>> beyond repair
>> in the deep end.
>> Oh, wait. Aggressively what?
>> We Okay, new people around. So, I want
to change of pace. I'm going to go say
hi.
>> Okay.
>> Some new people.
>> What?
>> Apparently.
>> No.
>> Say hi to Wings Dinosaur.
There's this indent come from a foreign
landing
around.
>> Good to see you. Well,
>> so I'm just calling you're doing well. I
am
I am having a day.
>> Aren't we all? At the end of the day, I
just hope yours doesn't end up worse, as
the saying goes.
I see.
>> I need more lemons.
>> How many lemons have you acquired?
>> There's a lack of oxygen and a lack of
>> only the two you gave me.
>> I just need more
lemon.
Apparently, they infuse their mana in
the lemon and
something like that. I believe that's
how you describe that
reason as to why things are happening
because they can't process what actually
>> it gets in their eyes and then they
can't seek
>> the blind people imagination.
>> It starts making [ __ ] will scare you
to death.
>> Be careful.
>> Lady, we have found enough adventures.
It's
>> Oh, okay.
>> It's terrifying.
>> I was asked to help find fruits. So,
>> few seconds.
>> Probably a cult.
>> Speaking of cult. Hi,
>> Kiki.
>> You see me associated with anyways?
I think you might have one.
>> But like a weird one out the other side
>> worship feet or something.
>> Thankfully.
>> I find that unlikely.
>> Same here.
>> I'm willing to bet there are people who
wish they could just see as you see.
Perceive the world and speak within your
mind. You exclusively
>> mine too.
He's pretty. the cult of chat.
>> Yeah.
>> Never underestimate them.
>> Uh Cali,
you ever seen her? She's one of the
tailor
the hat.
>> Okay.
>> There's a lot of black hair and there's
a lot of people.
>> Has he been hallucinating?
>> Okay.
>> Don't make a comment.
>> Oh,
like beigish brownish skin.
If anything cult related ends up
happening, uh, well,
>> evil cult,
>> well, evil cult related to whatever this
is,
>> you can make sure.
>> Can you handle?
>> It makes so much sense. It's just chat
is just a patron that gives you
information in exchange for doing dumb
[ __ ]
I feel like there's a lot of
>> I feel like what you're saying is you do
dumb [ __ ] but cause bodily harm to
yourself or at least social standing
>> or just just harmful
>> seems to like it when I make fun of
Jackson
>> I mean hey
>> what do you think likes
>> everywhere
>> how would I surmise this far.
>> I don't know.
>> Ask.
>> Did they give you?
>> Did they give you algebra blast?
>> Did they give you like a blade? Do they
give you like a like a familiar
>> a book?
>> Information. Knowledge.
>> Knowledge can ask chat.
>> Did this someone did?
>> Oh, you know what? Chad,
>> what type? What type of patron are you?
Do you give your your warlock
>> a blade,
>> a book
>> or a chain specifically tied to a
familiar?
>> Chat says that tits
>> still
>> I see this as absolute win.
>> I see absolute win
>> was not
>> if I may make a note on it if you would
permit me.
He's going to reach into his uh bag of
holding and take out two of a sheared
off piece of metal and a chunk of stone.
>> Uh I managed to pick some samples
actually from the site and in the future
with Riff's permission I will be helping
and going to the dwarves at Ingot to get
the materials actually properly
carbonated and research. If you would
all just make your
if you wish to join.
>> So, we'll figure more about that in the
future.
>> Omega and I were thinking about some
kind of
>> spell. Well,
only spoken theory, nothing else.
>> Well, at least the achievement that we
need.
>> The slate is still there. Whatever is
left of it, probably not entire
sentences, but fractures, what time,
what language, what written language,
etc. could possibly be recovered.
>> Simple spell is
mend could fix it, but you have to
figure out what it goes where.
>> So, figuring out a spell for that,
>> that magic is very messed up there.
Well, no, more than just that. If we're
dealing with someone that can do that,
>> and they went out of their way to wipe
traces clean, it's probably not going to
be as easy as simple men's spell.
>> We're looking for the traces themselves.
Yes, they did this, but I don't think
they were the ones to a build it
>> and two that wasn't its purpose.
>> I don't think that's an assumption
though. So,
>> so you think it, so you think that tower
was designed to do something else and it
was that raised
>> and not to mention Omega raised an
interesting point where
there was a
very familiar looking
walkway
on the far side of the island, not
dissimilar from the Nexus walkway.
>> That's actually true. I saw that, but I
didn't want to jump to conclusions about
what its purpose was because we did see
a lot of imprints from different
structures during our time there.
>> It's possible that that place once was
connected to the Nexus. I recorded the
information, the
location data
>> and I'll try to
look through some books to figure out if
there ever was any kind of point.
As much as they scrub,
they can't just scrub everything in all
existence. I hope
>> if that is the case, that would be a big
problem. It's probably a bigger problem
than whatever we're facing on a
>> just a thought.
>> Is there a possibility that a wasn't the
target?
That sounds stupid, but something of
that magnitude.
>> Is it
>> a test?
>> Is it possible? Maybe.
>> I have a confession to make.
>> I was interested, much like everyone
else was, and a lot of people went down
there because a lot of other people were
curious when the tunnels got blown open.
What's the deal with the vault beneath
us? Does anyone know?
>> Oh, well, that's the lead theory, isn't
it? But no one's been behind there as
far as I know. So, I don't think anyone
knows for sure. If we're approaching
this from your perspective, if someone
were diverting the lay lines for some
other reason, the magnitude of magic
innately that this island needs and or
is was through that vault.
>> Where's the frothing? If it were to be
pushed away and diverted somewhere else
in here,
>> that may be a reason why the island got
curved around. If
>> to prove this, we would have to see
instances of places of great magnitude
that suck in large amounts of magic also
suffering from the same effects of
Aether. I could talk to some of my info
my info brokers and such to see if
anything anywhere else is suffering just
to uh look into such a thought.
>> Was the idea yesterday was the idea
yesterday to see if there was other
places where this happened? I would
imagine
>> as as much as it happened here and it
all pulled lay lines in a certain
direction that we followed,
>> it seems centralized
>> but not
sensibly centralized.
If we can find other places that is
suffering the same effect and going
towards the same place, it will prove
your hypothesis and it'll be a actually
a good grounded theory as to what's
going on.
>> But for now, all we have is theory
crafting, I guess.
>> It's not bad.
Well, it's a good start. We have some
information, so better than nothing.
I heard about it only in concept. Light
and dark, positive and negative, the
upper and lower sides of the coin,
material and abyssal sea. the the the
concept of
>> there being an opposite to magic was
feasible because of pattern recognition.
But to see it in person,
that abyss on the other side,
it wasn't death. It wasn't absence of
nothing. It was
>> Oh, yeah.
>> It was incomprehensible.
>> I don't even know the word for it.
the growths.
>> Oh my god, I can't see them.
>> Well, that's probably because it's pure
anti-agic, right? It's just complete
blind spot.
>> Not even blind spot. It doesn't exist
for him.
>> Well, as a magical creature,
>> kind of made sense, I suppose. was about
hard to see.
>> Something that sucks in all light.
>> I imagine he sees it differently. Like
us not being able to see certain colors
on a spectrum.
It's probably like staring into the sun
for him,
>> a blot in the sky.
>> It's just alarming because it's another
form of something that defies magic
which we haven't seen before.
with
>> and this is what
>> more like another form of it.
>> Fourth.
>> Yeah. Personally,
>> fourth
>> aberrations
scar
dri
>> now this.
>> Now this
>> wouldn't that be technically
one?
Yeah, there would be shadow vein.
>> It's in it's uncomparable to any of
this.
>> No, I wouldn't say it was umbrell.
>> No, we're saying all the different forms
of
>> all the different forms of things we
should find.
>> Oh, right.
>> And this is this is new. It's not new.
It's quite ancient
>> problem because we haven't even
the power not there's none there's no
one to reach reach out to here. We don't
have a magistrate.
>> We do have Nox and he is a part of the
college of magi.
>> Well, that doesn't
magi.
>> No. Can't he reach out to college and
through the college of magi can they
contact the tower foration?
>> He could just contact the tower at that
point but the more like
>> Rafe has connections directed to the
tower as much as I know.
>> Yeah,
>> but we've heard nothing.
>> He has
>> Well, hold on. Anti-agic is pretty
[ __ ] taboo, right?
>> Ever since I've gotten here. Yes,
>> it's it's the tower.
>> Where would we find books on that?
>> Yeah, where would we find books on that?
>> We wouldn't
tower that under normally.
>> That would be contraband and that having
it would just put you in danger.
>> Yes,
>> I know. But I'm just saying that place
was old. Very old. And if that actually
was designed to do that, then we need
research on anti-magic,
which is going to be [ __ ] difficult.
Perhaps
we're going about this on the wrong term
keys we're searching for.
>> If it's something that old, it may base
it might find its links back all the way
to the war.
>> Historical records, documents of
battles, events from the war. If we
could find something similar to that in
any historical record, it'd be a start.
>> Yeah.
going off of a hypothetical carbon
dating.
>> That's why to get the dwarves in to
figure out what the stone in the metal
is only 4,000 years old.
>> Someone had a grudge against
specifically
>> and have to be in that albeit long time
frame, but that's still narrows it down.
>> That's his hypothetical. That's actually
a good
>> like what thing
>> I think four 5,000 years old
>> 5,000
>> I actually have a question to ask
>> how much do we know about Aether
>> I mean not like present day I mean
historically
>> how much do we know
>> uh during the
war way back when it used to be a
separatist or terrorist base for the
monastic night order.
>> At some point it used to be involving
the mage's college like everything else
>> that too
>> before it split
>> and now
eventually it was uh cleared out.
The magistrate was
instated and
it was very barren as much as I remember
from what Califax said about it.
>> Wait,
>> eventually lefay happened then
you're saying
>> this was a terrorist base and they
didn't let it fall into the sea.
As a matter of fact, an arch mage took
interest in it.
>> Why?
>> That's a pretty good [ __ ] question,
actually.
>> You know, could it be the vault?
>> Yeah, I about to say that door down
there could be like all of this place
itself.
>> He's going to reach into his pouch. He's
going he's going to flip through a few
pages on the door. On the door. I I
spent some time studing it. on the door.
It It had affinities, right? It had the
soul in the middle, but it also had soul
on the outside. Not just that, but two
other symbols.
>> Now, these could just be simple arcane.
Yes. No, no, no, no. It was it was soul
>> and then two others on the outside, but
soul was also in the middle. Now, this
could have been nothing. This could have
been just other runic symbols, but it
was on the same length and of the same
importance as the soul symbols. So, what
what were those two other symbols? Cuz
they're not on the affinity chart, are
they?
>> We could go look.
>> Uh, we could go look.
>> Yes, anchor is right there.
>> Let's go look right now. We can continue
talking as we do this. So,
>> but if if this was a terrace base,
>> it should already be long in the sea by
now. Why did they keep the island up
here if it was a terrorist base for the
last
over there.
Yeah.
What's going on?
Yeah. See what I mean? You see what I
mean?
You just don't do that.
something else. And right there is a
blank space.
Hold on. Actually, hold on.
>> I just realiz
I remember
the islands
and pieces.
>> I don't think that's enough to remember
the name because I know the name of the
island. So, it's not
>> disorder
arcane protection
mind
weird.
Mind
of those none of those clash, did they?
>> Do you see what I mean?
Actually,
I'm so glad I giving this
>> as a reward because I I kind of uh made
ging
with scholar pursuits. I have a book on
magical language
>> straight from the mages. Could I along
with Rift here look through it to see if
there's any
two symbols.
I'll give you a roll on that because
that's
because I need to confirm one or two
details first.
>> Understood.
>> You find a symbol. You find symbols
which look similar to those. You're not
a lead or it could simply be the way.
>> I have this book for two days in part to
the deal me. So I'll do some research
into this book to see if I can find
anything similar.
How dangerous
throughout all of history?
It's not impossible. It's not
impossible.
It's dangerous to the point of everyone
who has magic.
They almost look like
similar things to Holy Darkness.
This would the symbols that we're
>> that's empty
>> is part of the equation that this that
seals this door
>> can also be something to
>> only the support structure for affinity
clashes to not happen.
>> If soul by itself is so easy to
>> does it just require soul?
It requires a lot of knowledge and
practically
it requires
>> ar mage of soul
>> which I guess
would be able to
>> Yeah.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. No one who knows
mention
>> the outer symbols we don't know about
are not what are helping with the
affinities. It would have to be for the
door. Yes. The question is what are
those symbols? That's what I mainly
focus on is what those symbols
represent. What do they mean? Because
they're not on the affinity chart.
They're something else. Something not
recorded. Something that
>> no one commonly knows about. I mean,
what else could it be?
>> If I were to make an observation,
>> believe it or not, this is important.
>> Two of those
look like variations of darkness and
all. Specifically, the one that looks
like an eclipse and the one that looks
like a exaggerated squiggle.
>> That's true. It does look like
itations.
>> You're right. That Yeah, that looks like
the old ways of writing them down.
>> Could it be ancient crabs?
>> I
No. No, it wouldn't be because that'd be
all script. Yeah.
>> Hypothetically. Hypothetically.
I'm just Follow me here.
You just came out of a war that ruined a
lot of stuff that does magic. Yes,
>> it ruined magic in itself.
>> You would not want the populace to be
capable of recreating the spells and
such that caused all of this. So instead
of giving the actual
common arcana language of affinities in
their symbols, you make a diluted
version,
>> a newer version that
>> only lessens the draw. You make new
symbols that also can do the affinities
just slightly different.
>> Honestly, it's a plausible theory.
There's lots of different scripts which
do the same thing. to instate control.
>> Feel a bit uneasy.
>> Protection of magic.
>> Okay.
>> If the affinity circle or the affinity
chart that we know is merely a dumbed
down version of what it really looks
like,
what does that mean?
>> Opens a lot.
>> That it's very unusual. No one's found
it before, but
>> obviously it's to protect people. But
>> beyond that,
Well, to protect people. Yes,
>> obviously.
>> But
there aren't just arch mages who are we
say arch mage level strength.
>> Exactly.
>> And Kiki,
>> remember that time in the tower?
>> Uh,
>> what are you talking about? where we
forgot to turn on the dome.
>> Yes.
>> Oh,
>> exactly that.
>> We're not going to talk about it because
we shouldn't
>> because they Yeah, exactly.
>> Okay. Right.
>> There are powerful
>> that kind of
>> there are powerful individuals. Yeah.
very
>> that we don't know about.
>> If you had access to the true undiluted
version of the affinity tree and all the
symbols a part of it, you could achieve
quite the feats of magic. If it does
exist, hypothetically, if it does exist
and there's a stronger version out there
that the old people that are still
around have access to, it would explain
how they are still so powerful and yet
not cause any irreparable damage to the
weave. Because if now you can correct me
if I'm wrong, but
>> memory serves, if you do a powerful
enough
>> spell, it affects the weave.
>> And that is with the knowledge of this
of the the affinity trees and runes that
we do know.
>> It is usually what's the word? Um
>> hypotheticated.
If you were to fail such a cast, that's
when it's more pronounced the effect of
the waves. But there's chance and
believe in succeeding name
>> like yellow.
>> If you had access to
>> as a devil's advocate
>> to something more powerful,
you could draw more easily from the
weave with it being more accepting.
>> Hypothetically, this is all up in the
air and we don't even know if this thing
exists.
>> As a devil's advocate, if this was so
secretive and important, why would they
be so conspicuously exposed right here?
That's true. That actually is a good
point. But um
>> they could just lie on what it is.
>> Has anyone explained what they are?
>> That's what it's been explained when
they first appeared.
>> The maintenance room. The room where the
fight with the
>> where all the delicate magics are
condensed and managed.
>> But do we know that to be true? Unless
Unless we have a an account from someone
who asked about this to any of those in
charge before they left. Unless we had
that, all this is speculation on what
they would do if we left.
>> We would have to ask Rift then what the
what the magicians have said and we
don't even know if he, you know, tell us
the truth. We don't know.
>> Tempest is
>> Tempest is one of the people who casted
this spell.
>> Really?
>> It was Tempest. Yeah, we should talk
about it. I suppose
>> we would have to be very inconspicuous
in asking about it then
>> because we're asking a lot of very
dangerous questions here.
>> I I think he knows we're looking into it
given where we were and what we saw.
It's a pretty relevant question.
>> I don't think he'd be that annoyed at
us.
>> If you want to be my guest,
>> I'm just saying he's probably going to
find out we're looking into it one way
or the other.
>> I have a question. Is that off topic?
>> Yeah.
>> Mhm.
>> How much do you all know about Rift?
>> A lot.
>> Depends on what you mean.
>> He's connected to the tower. What do you
mean by that?
>> I can't tell you.
>> He has certain favors. That's all we can
say. He has certain privileges most
people do not get.
>> He knows someone who has sway. That's
all.
Yeah, he knows someone who has sway and
he's protected under them.
>> He mentioned a her. Can you tell me what
a her is?
>> Huh?
>> Actually,
>> female presumably.
>> He said that he would need to talk to
her in relation to the tower
propagation. Would you know her?
>> That's a get this is a guess that is not
connected. This is a complete guess for
me. Could be the arch mage of arcane. He
h
>> Archangel Arcane
>> could be
>> Arcane. Why Arcane?
>> Maybe Califax is Califax's wife. I think
they
>> have a relic made for me.
>> Who? Who are you?
>> That's true.
>> Yeah, that's true.
>> Can we help you?
>> I can't hear you.
>> I said I'm walking through here. I saw
some undead run out of the not
trying to see if I can find where it
went. Oh,
>> well, good luck to them.
>> Oh, we didn't see anyone of that, so
we'll run through here. But good luck to
you, though.
>> By the way, by the way, if you come
across a locked room with a bunch of
groaning coming from it, uh, that's not
an issue. It's handled.
>> Oh, cool.
>> Uh, apologies for jumping around the
place. Um, back to the topic at hand,
though, because obviously you don't want
to talk about it. Um,
>> we shouldn't. And it's, you know,
someone's privacy.
>> Of course,
>> those symbols.
>> You may ask him if you want to.
>> If those were original affinity symbols,
>> wouldn't they be the corresponding color
much like the ones in the object?
>> They're placed on the same color and or
level
>> of soul.
in the same category.
>> As much as that this is a splinter of a
memory from when Califax talked about
it.
>> Before the Sundering there were an
affinities.
>> That's not accurate. No, before the
Sundering there were affinities. You
could cast up and down the chain.
>> Right. That's the one.
>> And there was no affinity flashes. And I
don't know if soul magic was a thing for
sundering. I don't know if it was. I I
can't remember.
>> You know, you know, if you
>> soul magic wasn't a thing. Maybe
>> it was a rumor.
>> It was a rumor. I don't know. But this
isn't free.
>> Could
simply be a word in ancient Arcanum that
allows you to act with different
elements.
H
maybe
>> that would be Rift is the Rift's the
main one. So it's
>> because if soul is simply a warden in
Arcanum, it would make sense that these
two are also runes of Arcanum because
they're working in join to each other.
>> I could be completely wrong. I just a
little theory I had by looking at this
thing.
>> So you you see the three outer symbols.
>> Yeah. There's also three little circles
that surround the soul symbol. Maybe
those three like create souls somehow. I
don't know.
>> Maybe. But there's there's also in in
relation to that, there's an empty
socket right there on the outer symbol.
>> Yeah, that might not be empty.
>> That's one circle that that might be the
symbol.
>> So maybe there's a rune that you place
in the empty one which opens the door
>> or the or that is the symbol. It could
be a circle like the light of a sun
>> that mean it has light and then darkness
is the eclipse.
>> So like light darkness
>> maybe
>> wait
line light darkness
huh
>> I just remembered something from a long
time ago that might not be related.
The one time I remember reading about
bringing opposites together, which is
something we should not talk about
>> at all, but here
>> Califax tried a ritual of light and
dark.
He that was that was the polarity
conjunction he attempted. I don't know
what the spell was. I just know it was
light and dark. Yes. Light and dark
bound together with soul
>> and it failed. It killed most of
>> It killed most of his students who were
master majors.
>> Oh my god. I know what you're talking
about.
>> Wait, what?
>> Yeah.
>> When was that?
>> That's why no one talks about them a
long time ago.
>> No one insanely dangerous.
>> You know, teach at the college. That was
7,000.
>> Wait, 7,000. So before he became the
magistrate of a
>> Yeah. Very very very
>> close enough.
>> Can I get another
confirm?
>> That's a 10.
>> I'd say is he not?
He did do something similar on the
island once. I think it involved too.
>> Well, not indirectly. It was something
about mixing rocks with nature,
>> making it an abomination of plant.
Eventually caved in on itself, but it
was something you did. And then there
was something else that was more so
along the lines of shadow man magic
>> that removed lifts Rit's leg from his
body and it still moved around like
normal. That was a weird day.
>> Comfortable to be near such casting
then.
>> Yeah, tell me about it.
>> The thing about categorizing something
is that you can't account for all that
it's capable of. There are fires that
both can be flame and arcane and
everything else in between.
>> Just a thought.
>> Overlaps.
>> Yeah,
>> there are overlaps despite there being
polarity clashes.
Which leads to the question as to what
makes them different.
>> What is magma if not heated a proc? Heat
is fire. He is under fire.
>> Life to rock.
>> Is also about liquid
>> up and down the chain as you said.
>> I think it's best that we act as if this
conversation never happened.
>> Yeah. We still don't know what's behind
there as a thing.
>> Do we want to know?
>> Really?
>> Yes.
>> Well, it it's it seems relevant.
very
>> sometimes knowing a thing is to invoke a
thing.
>> It'll always seem relevant to know
what's back there. I imagine
>> I'd say we figure out the chain of
events that led to that thing being
locked away instead of learning what
that thing actually was cuz there's mind
on it
>> with Rift.
>> I guess there is one important thing to
know. You're automatically booted to the
Nexus that will kill you if you touch it
without the protections.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> I'm sorry. The only people
>> that
protection of the Nexus.
>> Yeah.
>> If you have any kind of magic rat tail,
feel free to touch it. It will actually
kill you.
>> Oh lord. All right.
>> Or it would if the island didn't
stop before you make proper
>> created the seal. Correct. It wasn't
here originally. Tempest Califax and
>> was part of the
>> part of it. So it's not
>> that is as we know that there was
because
>> I would also recommend without drawing
attention to ourselves
>> as much as we know Tempest
mind
soul califax.
>> Yeah.
And uh sulfur was
>> sulfur again.
>> Wasn't she like raw? She was old
mushroomy.
>> Oh no, she was Was she sage?
>> I don't remember.
>> If we're going off that, there are two
other affinities unaccounted for.
>> There was a time where the dragon
acted like a higher figure.
>> Did they?
>> I don't really like
>> I mean Do you know how many people are
involved with creating this seal?
>> No.
>> Again, from what I've heard, three, but
don't know that for a fact.
>> We know of three.
>> Just of three. It could have been anyone
else.
>> Even when even even when talking when we
talked to Tempest
>> when we talked to Tempest about it, he
also said three, but that could not be
the case. He could just say that it was
three.
>> We can't rule out lying. I just
>> Yeah.
>> Unless we can certify probably be lying
to protect someone, right?
>> Yes. Absolutely.
>> If there's someone that
>> cuz here's the thing, right?
>> We don't know much about the monastic
order of knights, right? Back in the
day,
>> they No, they got they're one of the
only groups that was so vile that the
tower decided to hunt them down.
>> They're dead. And this was one of their
bases. It's probably some relic still.
>> Well,
>> yeah. So yes, there would be traces of
the presence here. Maybe ruins of the
such.
>> Could this have been something that the
order built? I mean, there are knights
on either side.
>> Do we know their architecture? Do we
know what it looks like?
>> And then later got
>> No, the architecture would be nice.
>> How do we know that the arch mages even
made the seal?
>> Maybe they just maintain it.
explain the two other unknown rooms on
the outside.
>> That's true.
>> Unless those symbols on the outside are
meant to relate to an individual.
The one that looks kind of like soul
could be Califax. The one that looks
kind of like mind could be Tempest. And
the last one could be Sulfur.
>> So the runes are just signatures of
those that created it.
Well, they're also what lets people in
there.
>> From what I understand, people who can
go inside is either
>> we're going in circles. There's too many
factors that are
>> You're right. You're right. It's just
>> there's too many questions.
>> Let's finish this conversation off by
going over what we do in fact know and
what we're going to be going forward.
>> What we do know.
>> Yeah. Let's finish this conversation off
with what we do know and what we plan to
do with this going forward.
>> I can start off simply
>> before you start
as part of the major guild. We're not
touching this seal. It's already
malfunctioning. We're not touching it.
>> Malfunctioning?
>> Yes.
Very slightly, but it is. and it's
putting strain on the island.
Tempest said that he
patched it though patch is temporary.
We need a magistrate.
>> I'm sorry. Sorry, I knew I know we were
going to say we're going to finish this,
but I have like another thought that
just came to me.
>> In the historical news and through word
of mouth, I heard that you all faced
some sort of creature that had burrowed
into the island. Is this correct?
>> Their
beer?
>> Yeah.
>> I got here about 4 days before that
happened.
>> Do we know why it was here?
It was sucking on the island on it.
>> Well, yeah, but how did it get here?
>> How did it get here originally? Getting
>> out. Rumor.
>> What was it trying to get at? It was bur
It was burrowing into the ground.
>> What was rumor?
>> Want me to drag me into a channel? I can
tell you this out of character to a DM.
Um, I mean, you're allowed to say rumors
regardless. They're just rumors. But,
uh,
>> but I want to let you know in case you
don't know this is part of lore.
>> Okay. Uh, one second.
>> I was kind of rumored. That's not really
a rumor, but we say it's a rumor.
>> Mhm.
>> The thing was here to eat on something.
Who's used to say
>> last time I was here with with Rift
>> which was the person integral in
defeating the be here. As much as I
remember
that's
where it's corpse is or something like
that.
possibly. I don't remember exactly what
>> so many pieces here.
>> Okay,
>> right. It's very much vague, but if the
word of mouth was to be believed at the
time, it was rumored that it was
originally planted here
in an attempt to if you believe it or
not, kill Oroxy.
Like an assassination attempt.
>> Kill who? Oro, the golden dragon that
resides over the nexus.
>> This is the first time I'm hearing about
this person.
>> The one the one in charge of
>> well is kind of just arresting. Well, I
think they're related to tower, not one
the same.
>> They are a pure golden dragon.
>> It's the thing that's in charge of the
whole nexus and it just kind of sleeps.
Doesn't really do anything.
It needs a nexus and now it's taking a
very long nap.
>> I heard
that created the nexus. I didn't think
it was a singular dragon of the you know
of the fact that
gods do not have
>> yes
>> in this plane at all.
>> Yes.
>> Do they have snow?
That is the closest thing
as much as I was as much as I've been
remembered I've ever I can remember from
Califax's lesson.
The dragon one over the nexus and one
was in charge of the tower is the
strongest thing.
Assumably
>> it is.
>> It's not a gone. It doesn't call itself
a god, but it reigns.
>> Reigns supreme.
>> The golden dragon.
>> If that was an attempt to kill RX E, who
did it?
>> Cuz someone must have done it, right?
>> What is it? What are you looking at?
I'm just thinking to myself, sorry, I'm
not looking at anything.
>> I'd like to
>> This actually is a pretty
>> When I was about to leave for a couple
days,
>> you were doing something with the
crystal. Yes. It was the aftermath of uh
I think the um arc maid of arch mage of
light visiting. Yes.
Uh
yeah. Um remind me.
>> Uh well, all I remember is that you were
inspecting the big crystal for and the
surrounding ones to see if there's
anything wrong. And you told me that it
it seemed okay, but there was some sort
of
issue that
>> wasn't of concern.
>> I am getting slightly bored of this, but
I will find you later cuz I still wish
to cover.
>> Yes,
that was the
>> best of luck wrapping your head with
this.
That was what was not.
>> I'd like to investigate more of the
island itself if possible.
>> Let's see. Huh?
>> Everyone on your feet.
>> If I could,
>> we're not alone.
>> Get my hands on my
I don't know what that is.
That is Esie.
Hello, Esmare.
H
>> friend of yours.
Yes.
>> Do you know why the lay lines were on
the fritz that day?
>> The island's in general malfunctioning
in very small increments,
>> which does not seem coincidental.
Not to mention a day after that
the snow happened.
>> Well, a day or close to a week.
>> You know,
it's actually
my body will stop dying.
Isn't it the case that the island hasn't
fully restored itself yet? There are
those pillars on the ridges.
>> Yes, it's true. the islanders,
the more mana it gets, eventually it'll
grow.
>> Mhm.
>> Supposedly.
Don't know if you'll be able to do that
without Califax.
>> Why?
>> No, it won't.
>> Because Califax had to reconstruct the
lay lines within the stone that joined
the island.
>> Right.
>> Well, if we could convert your curiosity
to mana, perhaps. Did the island fall
apart because of them taking it from the
monastic knights? Or did it fall apart
just simply because they allowed it to?
>> Disrepair and all that.
>> That's a whole other can of worms. Uh
>> the island needed a lot of mana. If it
used to be full of a bunch of mage
knights, they'd probably have an excess
of mana that goes from that to being
owned by Califax and a few vagrants.
Then
>> less mana things start falling apart. So
I guess gas,
>> right? It would in fact disrepair.
>> That actually is an interesting idea. If
there are parts of this island that are
still down below that haven't been
screened yet by the arch mage, it would
still have the remnants of the monastic
night order, part of it that the college
hasn't gotten to yet.
>> Now that's interesting.
>> In theory, yeah,
>> if we were to
>> organize an expedition to go down,
>> we may be able to find the pieces that
haven't resurfaced yet.
To do that, we we'd risk bypassing the
protections, which means we'd have to
get the say so of Tempest. Otherwise,
all the protections on the island would
probably kick in.
>> You're not touching anything.
>> Intention
intentionally
intentionally harming the island will
infer
banishment.
That's one.
>> So, would exploring downward count as
harming?
>> We'd probably tunnel realistically.
>> Two, if we'd manage to tunnel and the
and it's considered damage,
we would get caved in eventually.
>> I would assume as it as it repairs
itself.
>> I would just assume it'd be down in the
clouds. I didn't think we'd be Or are
you saying we would be tunneling into
the clouds?
>> I was assuming going down from
>> No, I mean like the the the the parts of
the island that have fallen into the sea
of clouds into the astral sea. I'm
talking about those parts, not the stuff
that's here yet.
>> If they're in the astral sea, they've
probably been in a drift for hundreds of
years at least.
>> So, who knows where they could have gone
at this stage cuz the astral sea is
there's no gravity. There's no energy.
far to the east.
>> Scattered in the wind.
>> That's [ __ ] scary.
>> I I don't think it's that simple.
>> You did
>> You didn't You did say it looks similar
to the other bridge.
>> It did.
That's
>> that's a hell of
>> Well, I don't know what y'all are
referencing.
>> We went to investigate what's been
causing this loaded sentence,
>> the snow and everything else.
>> Yeah, that's um
that's something
>> you're implying that whatever we were at
was part of the island.
>> I know that is a very high that is a
very big maybe
>> question. Uh, now that I know the
>> distance,
>> how far was that?
>> I add a character. I did choreograph
like the the map. I I did all that and I
figure out the trajectory generally of
where it was.
>> I mean, you don't know. So, it was a
ways off, but given the fact that you
don't know the rate at which the
island's been decaying,
>> in theory, it's possible.
No, I have the location.
You have the location. You have
location.
>> How far if we flew straight? Imagine.
Let's Let's imagine. Let's imagine we
flew straight. How far?
>> It's quite a ways away.
>> I I'm sorry. I don't have it in like
erroromical units.
>> Take out the remnants of the stone I got
from that island.
Now I'm going to look over at that
thing.
Huh?
>> Oh god, I wish we had a dwarf or
something with us. God,
>> cuz we could we could confirm this right
now cuz we have a stone with us right
now.
>> Master craftsman on the island as much
as I know.
>> Don't know if he's alive. I didn't see
him.
>> I saw him here today.
>> He was here. If we could just get
someone who knows masonry, we could
confirm this right now. If this stone
was a part of this island,
>> he was here. He's definitely not here
now.
>> Okay,
>> then we leave it till tomorrow.
>> Yes,
we can convene on this tomorrow.
>> If no one else is doing anything
tomorrow, we can convene on this because
I did promise Rift I'd look into the
metal and the stone that was on that
island and I was going to take it to
Ingot.
Okay,
>> if we're right about this,
you know the implications, right?
>> Whatever did what it did to the island
was part of the island.
>> Well, that also means they're going
after the island.
Yeah, that's
>> Yeah.
Who would know how to use other
machinery?
>> The same person that went missing a
couple days ago. And who was in charge?
>> No.
>> Could also be that there were
instructions there and that's why
everything was wiped clean.
>> That too.
Just saying. If we're saying that
assumption this is architecture from the
monastic order and let's say it does
match up
and that
machine
magical machine
caused that
>> who could have gotten it to work
>> members from the monastic order.
>> The only problem with that is they have
been wiped out for 4,000 years or more.
It's not impossible.
>> It's not impossible, but realistically,
>> survivors would have had a hell of a
long time to plan their revenge.
>> It's It could be survivors, but it could
also be other people picking up the same
branch. That's not It hasn't
>> Where would you even find information on
the monastic order or or the research?
>> What if there's wait
archaeologists?
>> That too. You mentioned it though.
>> What if
>> what if somewhere there's a dig site or
something and they've unearthed a
[ __ ] monastic order archive
>> with that all of the information on how
this place was run.
>> If someone had that
>> nearby
nearby the second scar there was a there
was a monastery of the
>> right of the massacre that was by the
order. Who's to say that islands like
Aether, if they were bases for the
monastic order, there are not similar
places like Aether out there? Maybe
having entirely fallen into the sea.
Maybe not categorized. Hell, maybe even
not found.
>> Not part of the bubble anymore.
>> Exactly.
>> Out of the mind's eye, out of the reach
of the nexus,
reached by
ship.
not something you would travel by
normally.
>> There's a lot.
>> That's the most likely one, though.
>> What we need to focus on now is figuring
out
>> what this stone and metal is from or if
it's even related to the island.
>> It's not always
>> it's the next step.
>> It's not always the most likely option
that has happened. Just as we discovered
with the lay line,
>> right,
>> disintegrating that
>> lay being moved like this and the
>> wasn't the most likely,
>> but it was the one that happened,
>> right?
>> It was intentional.
>> All the the door the doors swung open.
Anything could be possible. And we could
speculate on every single possibility,
but it's as
I'm sorry, I don't believe I ever caught
your name.
>> That's Stern.
Stern.
>> Stern. Small tale. You may refer to me
as such. Pleasure to meet you. As Stern
said, these are all just whatifs. But
the most likely next step that we can do
to figure this out is to find out the
origin of where that island came from.
And the best way to do that is to go to
Ingatop and have the dwarfs look over
the pieces that we found. and then maybe
take a dwarf with us here and have them
compare have a comparison of the stone
just to put this to bed. That seems like
the most likely next step for us to
take.
>> I think that's the next step that you
should take
>> flowers that we found.
>> What are you going to do on that same
island?
>> You're more of a botist than anyone
else. So, sure.
>> I am very much
>> Well, [ __ ] you have you took flowers.
So, you have a flower on your hat. You
do the Oh, no. You don't anyway. Look,
>> it's a sunflower.
>> I'm just I'm just saying.
>> Did you?
>> You can investigate that. Me and Stern
can Well, I don't know what Stern's
going to do, but I know for a fact that
I'm going to try and get my hands on
some books that I really shouldn't get
shouldn't have access to. Just, you
know,
>> so the same as usual.
>> I can continue work cuz I did get that
magical language book from Rift as a
reward for doing this for at least two
days. So we can both um if you wish to
assist me, we could both look over that
book together.
>> Yeah, I have quite extensive knowledge
on various magical languages. So there
should be a yeah
to if flowers like I collected guru on
the the island before about all I'm
going to do.
>> I think we have a good uh starting off
point then. We have a lot of uh paths we
can take to investigate this. That's
good.
>> That's a good thing.
>> Yep.
>> I mostly collected these flowers to give
to Luminina and Sylvie, but you know
what? Whatever.
The thing we need to do right now, and
this is just me talking, but I think we
should just keep these whatifs to
ourselves and just investigate
cuz spreading around all these whatifs
is going to create very
hostiles.
>> Yes.
>> Yep. Sounds like a plan.
>> We can work on us as much as you want.
Help. bring on people to help. But let's
keep the reasons
vague.
>> About things until we know for sure.
>> Until we know for sure what actually is
the truth. These possibilities are just
up in the air right now.
>> Sounds fine to me. Okay.
>> Wonderful.
>> I'm going to head for the darkness cave
and take a breather.
>> Uh yes.
>> So, best of luck.
>> Yes. Would I be able to chitchat you
once you're ready?
>> We can talk later. I just need some
help.
>> Yeah, I said when you're ready.
>> Yeah, I you you'll find me later. I
promise.
>> See you around. Uh Red,
>> did you did you almost call him rift?
>> Shush.
>> What a time to be alive.
I will be off.
>> I think Stern is nodding.
>> I think they're internally processing. I
will be off as well. Best of luck to all
of you.
>> If you're tired, get some sleep.
Goodbye.
>> I'm probably going to I'm probably going
to get off.
>> Go watch
those.
Just thinking about the
>> You can think clear thoughts.
>> Could you leave for a moment?
>> Oh, could you leave for a moment?
>> They were literally
>> just bouncing around.
>> I know. Just for a moment.
>> You will come back in a second then.
>> You know about this as well. When we
were in the tower and the arch mage,
two arch mages showed up that we were
shouldn't be there and discussing
something and looking at stuff.
>> They specifically talked about the
monastic order
>> again. If either survivors or new people
picked up the flag,
>> I'll have to go back through my
memories.
It's not unlikely. Again, throughout
history, some people, even though it was
a bad cause, picked up remnants.
>> All right.
>> Go nap. You're not going to remember
anything if you're [ __ ] tired, as they
say. True.
I'm going to go now.
Not always. I don't know. I have to ask
the Lord about that one.
>> Hello again.
>> Uh, [ __ ] What was your name again?
>> Not you. Sorry. Tells me that I have to
talk to the mayor and I'm going to go
into your name.
sword.
>> It sounds like someone's in
>> there.
I didn't get to get to say hello to him.
>> Someone greedy presumably.
>> All right. All right. All right. I'm
trying to get out
>> consent. appreciate it.
>> Yeah, he on his way to a diplomat
meeting of some sort.
>> No, you didn't let me get out. Okay,
>> I am gonna save you.
>> I don't know what it looks like.
>> Don't worry, sir.
>> I got you. Where'd he go?
>> I got it.
>> You're going to get hit with a hammer.
>> You spit him out now. I'm right here.
>> All right.
>> Thanks. Because of you,
>> like both and have left. You ruin
everything.
Waxy.
I'm going to I'm going to pop out.
My stomach is not being the most
agreeable right now.