DM: Welcome back to Aldara, everyone. Before we pick up where we left off, let me set the stage.
DM: The kingdom of Aldara was founded three hundred years ago, at the dawn of the Second Age, by Corwin the Elder.
DM: Corwin was the grandfather of the man who sits the throne today, King Theron.
DM: The capital, Highmoor, is built on the white cliffs above the Gray Sea.
DM: Most of Aldara's grain comes from the Vale of Orin, inland to the south.
DM: Now, two hundred years ago, Aldara fought the War of the Dusk against the elves of the north.
DM: The elven city of Vethran was burned to the ground in the last year of that war.
DM: The surviving elves withdrew beyond the Frostspine Mountains, and no elf has set foot in Aldara since.
DM: The war is why every Aldaran town still keeps a watch-bell to this day.
DM: You step into the Salt Hound, the only inn in Highmoor's lower city. The innkeeper, a one-eyed woman named Brisa, leans over the bar.
DM (as Brisa): You want my advice, travellers? Keep well clear of the old Corwin crypt.
DM (as Brisa): They say the founding king was no mortal man. Half-fae, my gran told me, and his whole bloodline cursed for it.
Player-Mara: Aldwin sets down her cup and answers her.
Player-Mara (as Sister Aldwin): I was raised in the temple of the Dawnmother, up in Highmoor. The sisters took me in as a child.
Player-Mara (as Sister Aldwin): The War of the Dusk left me an orphan. The temple was the only home I ever had.
DM: The throne room doors give way. King Theron is on his feet, reaching for the alarm bell.
Player-Tomas: Garrick doesn't hesitate. I hurl my dagger at the king. That's... a 23 to hit.
DM: More than enough. The blade takes Theron in the throat.
DM: King Theron is dead before he strikes the marble floor. The throne of Aldara now sits empty, and Theron left no heir.
Player-Mara: Gods. We just killed the king.
DM: Four palace guards pour in from the side passage. Everyone roll initiative.
Player-Mara: Initiative is a 14.
Player-Tomas: I got an 8. Ugh.
DM: Guards go first. The lead guard swings at Garrick — that's a 16 against your armor, it hits. Take 7 slashing damage.
Player-Tomas: Down to 22 hit points. I swing back with my axe — 19 to hit.
DM: You drop him. Two guards still standing.
Player-Mara: I cast sacred flame on the nearest one.
DM: With the last guard down, you sprint for the servants' gate.
DM: You slip out into the night and ride hard for the north road.
DM: Three days of cold travel bring you into the foothills, far from Highmoor.
Player-Tomas: Wait, hang on — can I even use my reaction while I'm prone? Let me grab the book.
DM: Uh, hold on. Okay, being prone doesn't stop your reaction, it just gives disadvantage on the attack roll.
Player-Mara: Cool. Hey, did anyone actually order the food yet?
DM: Pizza's on the way. Let's take five and pick it back up after the break.